这是刚被杀害的杰克·库南
Meet the late Jack Coonan.
这名字很耳熟
Why is that name familiar?
因为这几年我们抓过他
Because it probably crossed over all our desks
几十次了
a dozen times in the last few years.
暴力伤害  持械攻击  纵火
Aggravated assault, A.D.W., arson.
库南的案底很厚
Coonan had a heavy rep.
有消息说他是西部联盟的打手
Word is he's an enforcer for the Westies.
拜托解释下西部联盟
Okay, remind me--who are the Westies again?
"地狱厨房"(真人秀)出来的爱尔兰黑手党
Irish mafia out of Hell's Kitchen.
主要罪行是盗窃  造假  敲诈
They deal in cargo theft, counterfeiting, extortion.
爱尔兰国庆日
And public urination
在公众场所小便
on St. Patrick's day.
库南家中有防盗安全系统
Our boy Coonan also had a home security system.
12毫米口径的空心弹
12-gauge, hollow point.
巨熊穿防弹背心也顶不住这子弹
That thing could stop a kodiak in kevlar.
他要提防的会是什么人物呢
Who did he think was coming through the door?
不管是谁
Well, whoever it was
在死者身上留下了约30个窟窿
left him leaking from about 30 holes,
一般的35岁健康男性
that don't normally appear
不会如此死于非命
in a healthy 35-year-old male.
9毫米口径的手枪还别在腰带上
9-millimeter Sig still in his waistband.
他连拔枪的机会都没有
Didn't even have time to pull it out.
死者全副武装地备战
This guy was armed and ready,
证明凶手是相当厉害的人物
whoever got him was very, very good.
忍者刺客
Ninja assassin.
忍者刺客  这名字是不是重复了
Ninja assassin? Isn't that kind of redundant?
所有忍者不都是被定义为刺客吗
Aren't all ninjas by definition assassins?
别挑刺了  两位作家
Fine, Webster and Roget.
我们的忍者  也就是刺客
Our ninja-- assassination implied by definition--
顺着墙爬上来  从窗户潜进
scales the building, slips in through this window,
然后藏在  我也不知道  大概在
and then hides himself, I don't know, about...
看这个
Hey...look at this,
死者居然是强尼·王的粉丝
our victim's a Johnny Vong fan.
居然有人会买这个  真意外
Somebody actually bought those tapes? What?
强尼·王是谁
Who's Johnny Vong?
你开玩笑吧
Come on. You're kidding me.
全纽约的失眠人士都知道强尼·王的名号
Every insomniac in New York knows who Johnny Vong is.
整晚都是他的广告
His infomercial runs all night.
大多数人觉得
Most people think
有钱了才能让钱生钱
you gotta have money to make money.
但这不是正确想法  看看我
But that's not true. Look at me.
当我来到这个国家时  一无所有
When I come to this country, I come with nothing.
我坐船来  但是现在
I come on boat, and now...
-我有自己的船  -我有自己的船
- I own a boat. - I own a boat.
你的朋友们可能会这样说
Your friends might tell...
抱歉  大家能不能
I'm sorry. Do you guys mind
先处理完地毯上的死者
if we finish dealing with the dead guy on the carpet?
死者的手机  看来也被刺了一刀
Cell phone. Looks like it took a direct hit from the knife.
让鉴证那边查查手机内存卡
Have tech pull the SIM card.
我要知道库南死前与谁通过电话
I want to know who Coonan was talking to before he died.
莱恩
Ryan?
好
Oh.
我哥哥死得很痛苦吗
Did, uh... Did my brother suffer?
是的
Yes.
感谢你如实相告
Thank you for your honesty.
你原本可能会骗我
I guess you coulda lied to me.
不会  因为 我也有过相同的经历
No, I couldn't. I've been on your side of the table.
当时  我只想知道真相
And when I was, what I needed most was the truth.
我
I, uh...
我在阿富汗建学校
I build schools in Afghanistan.
让当地的孩子有机会靠努力而成功
You know, give kids over there a fighting chance.
我广受赞誉
I get all this recognition.
可我的哥哥杰克
And here's my big brother Jacky,
正是他教会我为弱者出头
the guy who taught me to fight for the little guy...
他又得到了什么
and what does he get?
他罪不至此
Worse than he deserved.
我不是为他的所做所为找借口
I make no excuses for the things my brother did,
但在成长过程中  我们只能靠自己
but growing up, we were on our own a lot.
杰克是街上最厉害的小孩
Jacky was the toughest kid on the block.
也正因为这样  引起了洛克的注意
That's what first brought him to Rourke's attention.
冯·洛克
Finn Rourke?
是
Mm-hmm.
他掌管西部联盟
He runs the Westies.
那你哥哥为冯做什么工作
What did he actually do for Finn?
杰克从来没说过
Jacky never said.
不管他是做什么的
But whatever it was...
都因此害他丧命
pretty sure it got him killed.
卡塞尔
Castle.
西部联盟的人都是狠角色
These Westies can be pretty rough,
你确定不要留在车里等吗
so you sure you don't want to stay in the car?
才不呢
No way.
好  别说话  像个男人样儿
Okay. Keep your mouth shut and try to butch up a little.
我找冯·洛克
I'm looking for Finn Rourke.
是这样吗
Is that right?
我这样觉得
Well, as far as I'm concerned,
你和这个娘娘腔可以自己慢慢找
you and your wife there can keep looking.
那么警告你
This is the part where I tell you
只要我打个电话
that one phone call from me,
卫生部就会来这里检查
and the Department of Health will be down here.
我保证你一个月不能营业
You'll be shut down for 30 days. I guarantee it.
真想要给你老板这个结果吗
Do you really want to do that to your boss?
我又不是叫你认罪
It's not like I'm asking you to cough up--
悠着点儿  我都听不见比赛了
Come on now. I can't hear the game.
汤米  给漂亮小伙子一杯啤酒
Tommy, a pint for the pretty boy, eh?
让他的胃好受点
Settle his stomach.
谢谢
Thanks.
洛克先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Rourke, I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
来调查杰克·库南案件
I'm here about Jack Coonan.
原来你为此而来
And so you are.
你最后一次见到杰克·库南是什么时候
When did you last see Jack Coonan?
不记得了
I don't remember.
事实上  我们这里没人记得
In fact, none of us remember.
我想你将会发现卫生部
And I think you'll find the Department of Health
对我这儿的态度是很宽容的
take a very liberal attitude to my establishment.
现在我警告你
And this is the part where I tell you
一边儿凉快去  探长
to pound sand, Detective.
走开
Step away.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我
Me?
没事  我很好
Ah. No. I'm good.
我的天啊
Oh... God.
马里奥·门多萨  花名朱雀
Mario Mendoza, also known as Trucho.
因在皇后区贩毒蹲了四年
You did four years upstate for distribution in Queens,
刚刚获得假释
and you just got off of parole.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
我手上有个西部联盟成员被杀的案子
I've got a dead Westie on my hands.
看起来你脱不了干系
And it looked like you were about to join.
告诉我你在冯·洛克酒吧的休息室做什么
So you want to tell me what you were doing in Finn Rourke's back room?
我可以讲真话吗
Can I be real with you?
-请讲  -我喝太多了
- Oh, please do. - I had too much to drink
然后我一不小心就摔倒了
and I accidentally fell.
-你摔倒了  -我摔倒了
- You fell? - I fell.
那你眼睛上的伤怎么来的
Well, then how'd you get that mouse on your eye?
我撞到墙上了
I ran into the wall.
那你的手又是怎么烧伤的
How'd you burn your hand?
我撞到墙后就摔倒了
After I ran into the wall and I fell,
我把手撑在烤架上
I put my hand out on the grill,
防止摔倒
just to break my fall.
那么谢谢你的真话
Well, thanks for keeping it real.
听着  我明白
Look, I get it--
这些所谓出来混的规矩
the whole "Street code" thing and all.
依我的经验  马里奥  像你这样的
But in my experience, Mario, guys like you
早晚又会因为什么被逮住
end up catching another case sooner or later,
在你被逮住的时候
and when you do,
难道你不想有个探长罩着你吗
wouldn't you like to have a Detective on your side?
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
我舒服着呢
I'm good.
上次是我抓的他
He was my collar from back in the day.
他替拉丁之王贩毒
Guy ran dope for the Latin Kings.
-拉丁之王  -是一个街头暴力帮派
- Latin Kings? - It's a violent street gang.
主要贩卖妇女与毒品
They mostly peddle girls and drugs.
朱雀是他们的打手
Yeah, Trucho's their blade man
用刀高手
real handy with the knife.
并未因谋杀被抓过
We never popped him for murder,
但是被他弄得手指头少几根的很多
but, uh, I met plenty of folks with fingers missing.
这么说这两个帮派间有过节
So was there bad blood between them?
他们两帮就像
Yeah, they're like the, uh,
"地狱厨房"一般狗咬狗
Hatfields and McCoys of Hell's Kitchen.
西部联盟觉得是拉丁之王杀了库南
So the Westies figure that the Latin Kings killed Coonan,
于是他们抓了拉丁之王的打手
and they snatch their blade guy and bring him in
对他进行拷问
for a little enhanced interrogation.
但这事没人愿意承担责任
Which no one wants to admit to.
依我的经验来看
Uh-huh. Look, my experience--
如果冯冲着他去  肯定是有原因的
if Finn went all get on him, it was for a reason.
西部联盟成员尸体上如果有窟窿
You got a Westie with holes in him,
朱雀很有可能就是凶手
Trucho's probably your guy.
他说得没错  我们找到了朱雀的车
He's right. We found Trucho's vehicle
停在雷哥公园里的小酒吧后巷
in an alley behind a little bodega in Rego Park.
那里经常有毒品交易
It's a big dope spot.
他把他的"开信刀"
And he left his little letter opener
塞在了汽车防晒板后面
tucked behind the driver's side sun visor.
这不是凶器
That's not it.
-你看都没看  -我看了
- You didn't even look. - Sure I did.
这是把匕首  4英寸的大马士革钢刀
It's a stiletto, 4-inch Damascus blade,
对于这些伤口来说这把刀太小了
and it's way too small to make these wounds.
也许凶手用了不同的刀
Well, maybe he used a different knife.
这个朱雀有多高
Just how tall is this Trucho?
他有
He's, uh...
5英尺6英寸(167CM)
5'6".
-踮着脚才有  -那么他就不是凶手
- Standing on his toes. - Then he's not your guy.
这些伤口的行成角度
Thrust angle on these wounds
显示杀害库南的凶手高于6英尺(182CM)
indicate Coonan's killer was over 6'.
也许凶手没有用匕首
Well, maybe instead of using a stiletto,
他只是穿了细高跟鞋[与匕首同词]
he was wearing stilettos.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你还好吧
You okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
鉴证人员在库南的手机上有发现
Tech's got some hits off of Coonan's phone.
可能会有点突破
Maybe they can shed some light.
谢谢了  蕾妮
Thank you, Lanie.
最后一个电话
The last call
库南是打给纽约的一处固定电话
that Coonan made was to a New York landline.
因为内存卡损坏了
Because of the damage to the SIM,
号码中最后两位无法得知
it's missing the last two digits of the phone number.
那就是有99种组合可能
Well, that's 99 possibilities.
我们快点开始试吧  莱恩  我是说你开始
We better get dialing. Ryan, I'm looking at you.
不必了  所有组合的号码都属于同一号码源
Well, no, the numbers are all from the same phone tree.
接下来就更有意思了
Here's where it gets interesting.
所有号码都属于
They all trace back to the New York office
联调局纽约分部的
of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
一个爱尔兰街头恶棍
What's an irish street thug doing
和联调局的能谈什么
talking to the FBI?
我的计划很简单  连傻瓜都懂
My program is idiot-proof.
看我  我从未上过大学
Look at me. I never went to college.
贝克特  联邦探员到了
Yo, Beckett. Your FBI agent's here.
我是看《炮弹飞车》的录影带学英语
I learn English from V.H.S. Copy of "Cannonball Run"...
这套DVD不是证物吗
Wasn't that DVD supposed to be booked in as possible evidence?
没错  但是我想可能有线索
Yeah, but, you know, I thought the might be something--
放回去
Put it back.
好吧
Okay.
福瑞斯特探员  感谢您大驾光临
I appreciate your coming down, agent Forrest.
您的多数同僚会要求警局警员配合查案
Most of your FBI colleagues would expect the locals to come to them.
我的多数同事只担心洗发水和记者招待会
Most of my colleagues worry about hair products and press conferences
其实他们应该出去捉拿犯人
when they should be out catching bad men.
我想您不是那样的人
I take it you're not from around these parts.
当然不是  先生
No, sir.
我不是  但是因为我的过错
I'm not. But for my many sins,
联调局把我调到纽约分部
the Bureau has transferred me here to New York.
您是怎么接触到杰克·库南的
How did you come into contact with Jack Coonan?
约一周前  他找到我们
He reached out to us about a week ago.
您就雇佣他为线人
And you signed him on as an informant.
没有
Nope.
为什么不
Why not?
这样的人太多了
'cause all there were overtures.
我不指望
And I wasn't about to
用母牛换仙豆[童话《杰克和仙豆》]
trade the family cow for a bunch of magic beans.
你不相信他
You didn't trust him?
库南这种人找联调局
When a case like Coonan reaches out to the Bureau,
通常是因为和老板作对
it's usually 'cause he crossed his bosses.
他手头紧  想和联调局交易
And he's hard up to trade them in to the Bureau
尽快加入证人保护计划
for a quick trip into the waiting arms of Witsec.
库南揭发的谁
Who was Coonan offering up?
并未知晓
Never found out.
肯定有人听到风声
Well, whoever it was must have gotten wind of it.
在库南向联调局告发前
And then killed Coonan before he had a chance
将他杀害
to deliver them to the FBI.
西部联盟有点像流氓国家伊朗
The Westies are a bit like the rogue state of Iran
也像伟大的德克萨斯州
and the great state of Texas.
对于判决死刑  他们绝不心慈手软
They're not too shy in handing out the death penalty.
向联调局告密  绝对是死路一条
And talking to the FBI is definitely a capital offense.
我们还得和冯·洛克谈谈
We need to talk to Finn Rourke again.
两天前  天使驾临杰克的家中
An angel visited Jacky's home two nights ago.
就是带走法老长子的那位天使
Same angel as took the pharaoh's firstborn.
我知道  你们当中有人不知道死亡天使
Now I know some of you think you don't know the angel of death.
但是相信我  他认识你们
But trust me, lads. He knows you.
所以
So...
敬亲爱的杰克
Here's to darlin' Jacky.
敬杰克
To Jay.
如果他现在魂在天堂
Huh? If he's up in heaven now,
肯定是趁天上魂灵做晚祷
You can be sure he broke in
才进去的
when they was at Vespers.
我希望你们是来悼念死者的
Come to honor the dead I hope.
若不是  我将感谢你们离开这里
If not, I'll thank you to move away out of this place.
你撒谎
You're lying.
你很清楚杰克·库南是怎么死的
You know exactly what happened to Jack Coonan.
匆匆审了朱雀
That once-over that you gave Trucho
只为做戏脱身
was just a piece of theater to throw them all off,
你的悼词也不过是做戏
just like your eulogy.
小心你的措辞  探长
Now you be careful, Detective.
不然呢  杀了我吗  就像杀库南那样
Or else what? You'll kill me just like you killed Coonan
他一向联调局告发你  就杀了他
after he went to the feds about you?
够了
Enough.
不准你诬蔑他
I'll not have you slander him like this.
今晚不准
Not tonight.
这是联调局告诉我的
I got it straight from the FBI.
杰克刚联络联邦探员  就被杀害
Jack reached out to them just before he died.
他告发你  是吗
He turned on you, didn't he?
你可别瞎说  小子
You don't know what you're talking about, boy-o.
杰克·库南一直到死  都是忠心耿耿
Jacky Coonan was loyal to his last breath.
他临终时蒙受神恩
He died in a state of grace.
就算你说的是真的
Even if what you say is true,
可以肯定的是杰克没有出卖我们
you can be sure Jacky wasn't talking to the g's about any of us.
你如何肯定
How can you be so sure?
你听过我的大名
You've heard of me.
知道我是歹徒  是盗贼
You've heard I'm a gangster and a thief.
可以肯定
Surely...
你知道  我杀过人
You've heard I've killed men.
回答我  探长
But you answer me this, Detective.
你听说过冯·洛克贩卖毒品吗
Have you ever heard of Finn Rourke running drugs?
有人栽赃陷害我
Someone was bringing it in here,
在我的地盘  我的后院  出售毒品
into my neighborhood, my backyard.
我派杰克去调查幕后的狗杂种
I sent Jacky to find the bastards behind it--
揪出他们  再依据我们的规矩
find them and punish them...
惩罚他们
According to our rules.
但最终是他们惩罚了杰克
Only they punished him instead.
没错
Aye.
就是他们干的
That they did.
现在
Now...
如果你们有正当理由  可以逮捕我
If you have probable cause I suggest you arrest me now.
若没有  我提醒你们  这是私人派对
If not, I'll remind you, this is a private party.
我多谢你们  请滚出我的地盘
And I'll thank you to get the hell out of my place!
再来一杯
Another.
等等  卡塞尔  她不能直接跟出来
Give her a minute, Castle. She can't just follow us out.
-这太惹眼了  -你也注意到她了
- It would be too obvious.  - You noticed her?
我好歹是凶案组探长
I'm a Homicide Detective.
如果我只会一件事
If there's one thing I know how to spot,
那就是  那个女人有话要说
it's a lady looking to unburden herself.
她在找我们
She's looking for us.
别按喇叭  低点声  你会吓跑她的
No, no, no. Don't honk, deep throat. You'll spook her.
你好  我是莫利
Hi, I'm Molly.
你好  莫利  我是凯特
Hi, Molly. I'm Kate.
需要载你到哪里
Can we maybe give you a lift somewhere?
只要离开这儿就行
Anywhere but here.
我当然很清楚杰克的背景
Of course I knew Jack's reputation.
这也是他吸引我的地方
It's part of what attracted me to him.
怎么了
What?
凯特  你想说你没爱上过坏男人吗
You telling me you never had a thing for bad boys, Kate?
无可奉告
No comment.
杰克没提过去联调局的事吗
So Jack never mentioned going to the FBI?
杰克从不和我谈这些事
Jack never discussed business.
但我知道他想退出
But I knew he wanted out.
我们谈过  要远走高飞
We talked about... going somewhere far away.
上周杰克告诫我  他可能会先走一步
Last week, Jack warned me he might get there first.
杰克预料到会这样
Jack saw this coming?
我们每晚都在一起
We spent every night together.
没有我睡在他身边  他会失眠的
He couldn't get to sleep without me next to him.
但上周  他却不让我过去
But last week, he wouldn't even let me come over.
只有杰克
Anybody but Jack.
我应该想到他在秘密计划着什么
And I'd have thought he had something going on the side.
你从没想过吗
That never crossed your mind?
这是我和杰克相处的最后一晚
This is the last thing Jack ever gave me,
他给我的最后一样东西
on the last night I ever spent with him.
杰克说  如果事情变糟
Jack said if things broke bad,
就把这个交给警察
he wanted me to give this to the police.
你怎么知道这是车站储物柜的钥匙
And how do you know it's to a bus locker?
这就是车站储物柜的钥匙
It's always to a bus locker.
运输安全局拆掉了许多
T.S.A. Tore most of them out,
有些汽车总站是例外
but a few terminals still have them,
这里是离库南公寓最近的车站
and this one is the closest to Coonan's apartment.
等等  不  别打开
Wait. No, no, no. Wait. Don't do that.
怎么了
What?
一旦你打开  我们就会看到
Well, once you on it, then we'll know.
可能会是外星人的尸体
Could be an alien corpse in there,
失落的约柜[藏刻有十诫石板的木柜]
arc of the covenant...
或是强尼·王的DVD
or Johnny Vong DVDs.
开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
这就是库南想给联调局的
This is what Coonan wanted to give to the feds?
等等
Hold on.
不是
No.
这个才是
This is.
海洛因
Heroin.
刚才酷毙了
That was so cool just now.
-你喜欢  -像足《迈阿密风云》
- You like that? - Yeah, it was very "Miami Vice."
库南不是要向联调局告发同伙
Coonan wasn't going to the feds rat out his Westie pals.
他是奉冯·洛克之命
He was looking to rat out
要铲除那个毒贩
the drug dealer Finn Rourke sent him to find.
可惜毒贩换了脚本
Only the dealer flips the script.
在库南与联调局成交前  杀了他
Knifes Coonan before he can close the deal with the feds.
所以找到毒贩  就查到凶手
So then we find the dealer, and we find the killer.
这些包装盒写着DVD是在香港包装的
These boxes say the DVDs were packaged in Hong Kong.
肯定是在起运前  加了海洛因
Someone must be slipping their heroin in before they're shipped.
就是说这边的人肯定知道
Which means someone on this end had to know
哪些盒子装着毒品
which boxes contain the drugs.
这些盒子也装着走向富裕的秘密通道
And which boxes contain the secret path to financial independence.
怎么了
What?
肯定是强尼·王组织里的人
It had to be someone in Johnny Vong's organization.
如果你只是餐厅小工  没关系
I don't care if you're a busboy.
如果你围着绿围裙
I don't care if you wear the green apron
给用蓝牙耳机打电话的混蛋
and serve fancy coffee to a jerk
倒高级咖啡  也没关系
talking on his bluetooth.
我也曾和你们一样
I was like you once.
后来  我发现了改变我一生的秘密
Then I discovered the one secret that changed my whole life.
有人准备好了吗
Who out there is ready?
这地方让我想起我的第二次婚礼
This place reminds me of my second wedding.
准备好签约  过新生活吗
Who is ready to close escrow on a new life?
勇敢点
Come on!
别想着也脱掉袜子
Don't even think about taking them off.
如果你脱了  我就朝你喷胡椒粉
If you do, I will pepper spray you.
王先生
Mr. Vong.
加油
Yeah, you!
王先生  纽约警局凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Vong, I'm Detective Kate Beckett with the NYPD.
想问你一些问题
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
当然可以
Sure, sure, sure.
警方认为你有一位员工
We believe that one of your employees
利用你的供应链  走私海洛因到美国
was smuggling heroin into the country using your supply chain.
走私什么
Smuggle what?
海洛因
Smack.
介意我们查看你的
Would you mind if we looked into your--
买卖海洛因
Heroin trafficking--
足够坐10年牢
That's good for a 10-year prison bid.
我不会责怪你逃跑
So I don't blame you for running.
这完全搞错了
This is all a big mistake.
我从不碰毒品
I never do drugs.
毒品是窝囊废干的  我是个正经生意人
Drugs are for losers. I'm a businessman.
我努力帮人们完成他们的目标
I try to help people achieve their goals.
除非他们的目标是在你虚假的房地产系统
So long as their goals are to blow 300 bucks
砸上300美元
on your bogus real estate system.
不  我提供30天退款保证
No, listen, I offer you 30-day, money-back guarantee.
如果那时你还没有获利
If you don't start building wealth by then,
我无条件  全额退款
I refund all your money, no questions asked.
骗局会有这种好条件吗
Could I make that offer if this was some kind of scam?
有道理
The man has a point.
闭嘴  你不觉得他
Shut up. You don't think he--
不
No.
听着  这样  我不是缉毒警察
Look, here's the deal-- I'm not a dope cop.
我是凶案组警察
I'm a Homicide Detective.
所以  通常  我不管你做的生意
So usually I don't even bother with your sort of an operation.
但是我的问题  还有你的
But my problem, and yours,
是你为了掩盖走私海洛因
is the fact that you had Jack Coonan killed
就杀了杰克·库南
in order to hide your heroin smuggling.
等等  杰克·库南死了
Wait. Jack Coonan's dead?
小心点  强尼
Whoa. Careful there, Johnny.
你的口音开始没那么重了
Your accent's starting to fade a little.
听着  我不是偷渡来的
Look, I didn't come over on a boat, okay?
我从未去过老挝  我来自加州的丹维尔
I've never even been to Laos. I'm from Danville, California.
那这强尼·王是怎么回事
And this whole Johnny Vong thing?
没有人想从哈佛的工商管理硕士那
No one wants to buy a real estate system
买这个投资计划  但若是个
from a Harvard M.B.A., but show them an idiot
开着劳斯莱斯的笨蛋  他们却会买账
with a Rolls-Royce, and they'll knock down doors.
所以我才扮了强尼·王
So I played Johnny Vong.
大家都爱听霍雷肖·阿尔杰式[美国梦倡导者]的废话
You know, people want all that Horatio Alger crap,
我就投其所好喽
So that's what I give 'em.
顺便还卖海洛因
Well, that and heroin.
你到底对杰克·库南了解多少
How exactly did you know Jack Coonan?
听着  不管你自以为掌握了多少情报
Look, whatever you think you know,
我向你保证  我没杀库南
I promise you, I didn't kill Coonan.
你们得相信我
You have to believe me.
是吗  你的所有信息都是假的
Do I? Nothing about you is real.
不是的
No.
为了把节目在全国推广  我需要资金
I needed money to take the program national.
而他需要一个渠道把货弄到美国
He needed a way to get product into the country.
虽然很愚蠢  但一旦你和恶魔做了交易
It was stupid, but once you make a deal with the devil,
你就要听从他
You belong to him.
你要听从谁  你在为谁卖命
Who do you belong to? Who are you working for?
他会杀了我的
He'll kill me.
-我能保护你   -你不能  没人能
- I can protect you.  - You can't. Nobody can.
你不知道他有多神通广大
You don't know what he's capable of.
不相信  看杰克·库南就知道了
You don't believe me. Ask Jack Coonan.
听着  王先生  我
Look, Mr. Vong, I--
算了  我还是选择坐牢
No. I'll take my chances in prison.
我宁愿坐十年牢  也不想没命
I'd rather lose ten years of my life than all of it.
得罪他的老板
Whoever he's working for
比坐牢还糟糕
scares him a lot more than prison.
肯定有办法能让他开口
There has to be a way to get it out of him.
我们可以让他看帕里斯·希尔顿的视频
We could force him to watch Paris Hilton videos.
你想害我被告吗
You want me brought up on charges?
贝克特
Beckett?
蕾妮  你怎么到这儿来了
Hey Lanie, what are you doing here?
是有关库南的案子
Uh, it's about the Coonan case.
这是克拉克·默里博士
This is Dr. Clark Murray.
是个法医病理学家  我请他来协助鉴定
He's a forensic pathologist. I asked him to consult.
我是  凯特·贝克特探长
I'm, uh, Detective Kate Beckett.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔  小说家
This is Richard Castle, the novelist.
我们见过了
We've met.
看到伤口周围的
Note the rectangular bruising
矩形瘀伤了吗
around these wounds...
这里  还有这里
Here and here...
是用刀柄用力击打
Caused by the hilt of the knife striking with force enough
挤压皮肤所致
to compress the skin.
结果就是  伤痕
And as a result, the injuries
比实际刀身渗透的更深
penetrate deeper than the actual length of the blade.
他的刀磨得很锋利
He's also honed his blade so fine,
所以刀碰到骨头时  是很容易断的
It's brittle enough for bits to break when it strikes bone,
所以在两名死者体内
Which is why slivers of blade
都发现刀刃碎片
were found inside both of his victims.
现在我们已确认这些碎片
We now know those slivers
属于同一件凶器
come from the same murder weapon.
等等  两名死者  他杀了多少人
Wait, two victims? How many people has he killed?
我们知道的有五个
Five that we know of.
那么这是连环杀人案
So we're looking at a serial?
说对了一半
Well, yes and no.
我们确定对方是个职业杀手
We believe we're dealing with a professional,
接受过大量的军事训练
someone with extensive military training.
是雇佣杀手
A contract killer?
我对库南的伤口进行了断层重建
I used tomographic reconstruction of Coonan's wounds
做个凶器的三维模型
to generate a 3-D model of the blade used.
这是特种作战组织用的刀
It's a special operations group knife...
尤受第一次海湾战争的特种兵的亲睐
The kind favored by special forces in Gulf War one.
死者都是一刀毙命
He kills with a single blow
其他的伤口只为掩饰杀人手法
using these other wounds to camouflage the skill
这样  第一刀就无从辨别了
with which the initial stroke was delivered.
和十年前的那个凶手
The very same method and the very same weapon
所用的手法和凶器  完全相同
that the killer employed... ten years ago.
蕾妮
L-Lanie...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett,
我敢确定 杀害杰克·库南的凶手
there is no doubt in my mind that Jack Coonan was killed
和当年杀害你母亲的  是同一个人
by the same man who murdered your mother.
我是这个案子的负责人
I am the investigator of record on this case.
你无权对我隐瞒证据
You had no right to withhold evidence from me.
那你想我怎么做
Well, what did you expect?
上次卡塞尔试着和你谈
The last time Castle tried to talk to you
你母亲的案子时 你差点拧断他的脖子
about your mother's murder, you bit his head off.
别找借口  蕾妮
Please, Lanie.
我注意到了伤口很相似
I noticed the wound similarity.
就找默里博士帮忙
I reached out to Dr. Murray.
在证据确凿之前
I held off from telling you
我是没有告诉你
until I knew the evidence was rock-solid.
但贝克特  我们一确定就来找你了
Beckett, we came to you the moment we were sure.
贝克特  我能和你谈谈吗
Beckett. Can I have a word with you?
可怜人的止痛药
Poor man's painkiller.
我知道是因为你母亲被谋杀
I know your mother's murder
你才来到警队
was the reason you become a cop.
我也知道你第一次办她的案子时
And I know how you almost lost yourself
几乎迷失了自我
trying to solve her case the first time you tried.
但我觉得只要你准备好了  不论迟早
I figured sooner or later, when you were ready,
你会再次全力追查
you'd want to take another run at it.
我只是没想到这个凶手会再次犯案
I just never expected her killer to come around
给你这么重的打击
and sucker punch you like this.
凯特  听我说
Kate, listen to me.
你是我培养出的
You're the finest homicide
最优秀的警察  无人可比
I've ever trained, bar none.
可以的话  我希望你能继续查下去
And I want you to stay on this one, if you can.
如果你愿意的话
If you're up to it.
但作为你的长官
But I wouldn't be doing my job as your Captain
我必须问一句
if I didn't ask...
你能办好这个案子吗
Can you handle this?
抱歉  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
我办不到
I can't.
凯特
Kate.
凯蒂
Katie.
晚上好  爸爸
Hey, dad.
那  你发现什么了呢
So... what have you found?
还不知道
I don't know yet.
但确实吓坏了你
But enough to scare you.
是的
Yeah.
你从警校毕业的第一年
I didn't sleep well that whole first year
我没睡过一个踏实觉
after you got out of the Academy.
晚上我一听到警笛声
I'd hear sirens in the night
就会想像你身处于黑暗之中
and imagine you off in the darkness someplace.
我做噩梦  梦到你被黑夜吞噬
I had nightmares where it swallowed you whole.
爸爸  我不想错过这个机会
Dad, I don't want to lose this one.
你妈妈经常说  生活中
Your mother always said that life...
没有我们面对不了的事
never delivers anything that we can't handle.
她一生都坚信这点
I mean, she lived by that, you know?
这是约翰娜永恒不变的生活法则
Called it Johanna's immutable law of the universe.
有几年  我认为她错了
And for years, I thought she was wrong...
因为我无法面对失去她
because I couldn't handle losing her.
现在
Now...
我几乎能听到她在轻语
I can almost hear her whisper,
我说过的
"I told you so."
妈妈最爱的四个字
Four of mom's favorite words.
听我说
Look...
她对真相坚信不疑
She was a devout believer in the truth,
如果她现在在这里
and if she were here right now,
她会告诉你  真相绝对无法伤害你
she'd tell you, the truth can never hurt you.
可能是你妈妈通过这种方式
You know, this may be your mother's way
在帮助你  凯蒂
of reaching out to you, Katie...
她在提醒你  真相
and reminding you that the truth...
仍是你手中的武器
is still your weapon to wield,
而非他们的
not theirs.
晚上好
Hey.
进来吧
Come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
坚持住  孩子
Hang in there, kiddo.
谢谢  玛莎
Thank you, Martha.
饭菜在冰箱里  如果需要到楼上找我们
Leftovers in the fridge. Upstairs if you need us.
请坐吧
Please.
只要你需要  我愿意为你做任何事
I will do anything that you need,
包括什么都不做
including nothing,
如果你需要我这么做的话
if that's what you want.
我想要找出杀害我母亲的凶手
What I want is to find my mother's killer.
那我们得撬开强尼·王的嘴
Well, then we need to break Johnny Vong.
那就动手吧
So let's break him.
我得向你道歉  王先生
I owe you an apology, Mr. Vong.
因为过于匆忙
Apparently in my haste,
忘了告诉你你所享有的权利
I forgot to read you your Miranda rights.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
不  我记得很清楚  你告诉我了
No! I remember distinctly. You read them to me.
但我都放弃了  你说过  她说过
And I waived them all. You did. She did.
你肯定记得  对吧
You remember right?
抱歉  老兄  犯了个低级的错误
Sorry, man. It's a rookie mistake.
不  等等  你们不能这么做
What? No, wait. You can't--you can't do this.
如果我现在走出去了
If I walk out of here now,
他会以为我在和警方合作
he'll think I'm cooperating with the cops.
我就死翘翘了
I'll be dead by morning.
对  没错
Yes, you will.
或者告诉我你在替谁做事
Or you can tell me who you're working for,
我会保护你
and I will protect you.
迪克·库南
Dick Coonan.
我替迪克做事
I work for Dick.
你是说
You're telling me
杰克·库南的哥哥是个毒贩
Jack Coonan's brother is a drug trafficker?
他装的像吉米·卡特[美国第39位总统]
He comes off like Jimmy Carter,
但其实那些都是骗局
but it was all a scam
只为凑钱给种罂粟的军阀
to funnel money to the Warlords with the poppy fields.
没错  他是建了几所学校
Sure, he built a few schools,
以此对捐赠者有个交代
uh, so he had pictures for his donors,
但大部分资金都流入到毒品买卖里了
but, you know, most of the money funded his cartel.
所以只要是想要的毒品  他都能搞到
So he had access to all the dope he wanted.
他只是需要一个渠道把货弄到国内来
He just needed a way of getting it into the country.
自911以后  要想神不知鬼不觉地
You couldn't get an aspirin from Kabul to New York
从喀布尔弄粒阿司匹林到纽约  都很难
without somebody knowing about it, not since 9/11.
我要做的
All I had to do
是让他在我香港的工厂里装货
was let him package the drugs at my factory in Hong Kong.
一过海关
He'd pick up the dirty shipments
他就来接货
once they cleared customs.
然后再让拉丁之王拿去卖
And he had the Latin Kings put it on the street.
天衣无缝
Perfect system.
百密一疏的是  朱雀一时犯傻
Well, perfect until Trucho caught a case of stupid
竟然把毒品拿到西部联盟的地盘卖
and started selling in the Westies' territory.
于是他们就派杰克四处查探
And then that's what brought Jack sniffing around.
杰克威胁他  如果他不收手
Jack threatened to give him to the feds
就把事捅到联调局
unless he quit.
-杰克杀了他的亲大哥  -不是
- So Dick killed his own brother  - Oh, no.
杰克在西部联盟这么久
Jack had been with the Westies a long time.
他脑袋后面可都长着眼睛
He'd grown eyes in the back of his head.
迪克雇了个职业杀手
Dick hired a professional.
叫什么名字
What's his name?
他叫他拉斯伯恩
Uh, he called him Rathborne.
怎样找他
How do I find him?
去问迪克·库南
Ask Dick Coonan.
案子进展如何
So... Any, uh, progress
查出杀害我大哥的凶手了吗
on the son of a bitch who killed my brother?
就快找到了
We're close.
警方认为杰克被杀是因为
We think that Jack was killed after Rourke asked him
洛克派他去查一个毒贩
to hunt down a drug dealer.
看来西部联盟这几年在毒品战上
Turns out the Westies have done a pretty good job
守卫的是相当严密
with the war on drugs these past few years.
一点也不容许
Talk about zero tolerance.
在他们的地盘兜售毒品
The punishment for dealing drugs in their neighborhood
死路一条
is death.
但当他查探到那个毒贩
But when he tracked down this dealer,
因为某种原因  杰克没有狠心杀了他
for some reason, Jack didn't have the heart to kill him.
典型的杰克式做法
That is so Jacky.
他总是冒冒失失
He always led with his chin.
好像他这一生  都在期盼着
He went through life like he was expecting to
能获得最佳运动员奖
win the good sportsman award on trophy night.
少废话  库南
Cut the crap, Coonan.
对你的毒品金三角  我们一清二楚
We know all about your heroin triangle--
阿富汗  香港
Afghanistan, Hong Kong...
纽约
New York.
我们还知道  你雇了杀手
And we also know that you hired an assassin
名叫拉斯伯恩
named Rathborne
你命他在你哥哥向联调局告密前
to kill your brother before he went to
将他灭口
the feds about you.
拿出证据来
Prove it.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
已经十年了  那天我们回到家
Ten years since we came home
发现有位警察在等我们
and found that Detective waiting for us.
我和父亲跨过警戒线  走进那条小巷
Ten years since we crossed that yellow tape
已经十年了
and went into that alley.
每次走过犯罪现场的警戒线
And every time I cross the tape at a crime scene,
我都会想起那晚
I think of that night.
也正因为这样你才成为了一名好警察
That's what makes you such a good cop.
如果我让母亲失望了呢
What if I let her down?
你知道为什么我选择你
Do you know why I chose you
作为妮基·希特的创作原型
as my inspiration for Nikki Heat?
不知道  为什么
No. Why?
因为你个子高
Because you're tall.
现在进去吧  做好你的工作
Now go in there and do your job.
司法会计正在
I have forensic accountants
审查你的公司  库南先生
digging through your organization, Mr. Coonan.
只要有买卖海洛因的蛛丝马迹
If there's evidence of heroin trafficking,
他们就会找到
they will find it.
但现在这还不是你最大的问题
But that's not your biggest problem right now.
雇用拉斯伯恩这样的杀手
Hiring an assassin like Rathborne
表明你是有预谋的
shows premeditation,
也使现在的情形显得很特殊
and that makes this a special circumstance case.
注射死亡你都有资格排上
Which qualifies you for the needle.
现在我可以把这个
Now I am willing to take
特殊情形暂摆一边
the special circumstance allegations off the table
只要你供出拉斯伯恩
if you give me Rathborne.
现在唯一特殊的情形  探长
The only special circumstance here, Detective,
就是你找不到足够的证据起诉我
is your complete lack of evidence against me.
我有强尼·王做证人
I have Johnny Vong.
那个假装有口音  搞房地产骗局的家伙吗
The guy with the phony accent and the real estate scam?
这就是你最拿得出手的证据吗
Is that the best you can do?
你真情愿拿自己的性命赌
Are you really willing to bet your life
强尼的守口如瓶吗  库南先生
that Vong can't hold his mud, Mr. Coonan?
交出杀手  我会跟检查官求情
Give me the killer, and I will put the D.A. in the mood
对你只提出二级起诉
for a second-degree plea.
我们初次见面时
When we first met,
你告诉我  你也有类似的经历
you told me you'd been on the other side of this.
还记得吗
Remember?
那么这个是不是你现在急于
Now... could that be why you seem so eager
想抓到这个神秘杀手的原因
to get your hands on this myterious assassin?
因为我不得不这样猜想
Because if I had to guess,
你的亲人被谋杀了
I'd say that someone close to you was murdered,
你觉得拉斯伯恩就是那个凶手
and you think Rathborne had something to do with it.
看来我连猜想都不必了
But I don't have to guess, do I?
因为你的表情说明了一切
Because it's all over your face.
这并不会改变你的谋杀罪名成立
That still doesn't change the fact that you're guilty of murder.
也许会改变
Maybe not.
我为罪行豁免权付出的小小代价就是
But for the low, low price of transactional immunity,
我给你想要的答案
I can give you the closure you've been seeking.
拉斯伯恩交给你  我被释放
You get Rathborne, and I walk.
探长  这是我给你的最后机会
And that, Detective, is my final offer.
罪行豁免权  保罗
Transactional immunity, Paul,
我倾向于同意
and I'm inclined to give it to him.
据我们现在所知  拉斯伯恩已经杀了五个人
Rathborne has killed five that we know of,
其中一名还是我手下的母亲
including the mother of one of my people.
这可关系到我们的自己人  保罗
It's one of our own, Paul.
我记得以前这对市里来说是重要的
I remember that used to mean something in this town.
怎么样
Well?
他同意了  地方检查官
He went for it. The district attorney
将给库南豁免权  只要他交出拉斯伯恩
is gonna offer Coonan immunity if he gives us Rathborne.
我希望你明白自己到底在做什么
I hope you know what the hell you're doing.
描述一下他什么样子
Describe him.
和我差不多高
About my height.
看上去很普通  一点也不出众
Just so average, he's almost invisible.
你们是怎么认识的
How did you meet?
我们一起服过兵役
We were in the service together.
大家都说他
They said he'd been killed
在95年的训练演习中死了
back in a training exercise in '95.
但是大约一年前  我在一家酒吧
But then about a year ago, I'm sitting at a bar
一眼望过去  就看到了他这个鬼魂
and I glance across, and I'm looking at a ghost.
原来那时他没死  是被招募了
Turns out he'd actually been recruited back then, not killed,
去做一些
to do...
政府不愿意出面承认的勾当
Well, the bad stuff that governments like to deny.
你是怎样雇用他的
How'd you hire him?
他给了我电话号码
He'd given me the number
那是他在开曼群岛的代接电话
to his answering service in the Caymans.
然后他们给了我一个
And then they provided me
一次性的邮件地址
with a single-use e-mail address,
还有账号
a numbered account.
我发邮件告诉他们目标的姓名
E-mailed him the name of his target,
电汇  然后等着就行了
wired him the money and waited.
好的  现在这样做
Okay, here's the deal--
你联系拉斯伯恩  刺杀目标是王
You're gonna contact Rathborne with a contract on Vong.
你告诉他警方会押解王
You're gonna tell him that the police are taking him
去地方检查官的办公室提供证词
to the D.A.'s office for a deposition,
他的任务就是不留活口
that he can't make it there alive.
不是这样操作的
It doesn't work like that.
先付钱他才会下手  10万美金  没得商量
He wants his money up front. It's 100 grand, nonnegotiable.
10万  这点上头可没办法同意
100 grand? The city is never gonna agree to that.
如果你要抓住杀害她的凶手
Look, you want to catch her killer,
代价就是10万
the price is 100 grand.
我可不能把这么多钱扔到
I can't just shoot that kind of money out into space
可能收不回来的无底洞
without any hope of getting it back.
你不能  我可以  这笔钱算我的
You can't. I can. This one's on me.
-卡塞尔  -就这么说定了
- Castle! - Do we have a deal?
好
We do...
我客户的豁免权
but my client's immunity kicks in
从拉斯伯恩接受刺杀任务那一刻生效
the moment Rathborne accepts the contract,
只要电汇一完成就行
once the wire transfer is complete.
只要拉斯伯恩接下这笔生意
As soon as Rathborne takes the job,
就没你什么事了
your part is done.
-我就可以走了吗  -你可以走了
- And I walk? - And you walk.
拉斯伯恩已经上钩了
Rathborne has taken the bait.
今天的任务中  强尼·王
Now for today's performance, the role of Johnny Vong
将由警官克莱顿·李扮演
will be played by officer Clayton Lee.
做好殉职准备  敬礼
We are about to die, salute you.
莱恩和埃斯波西托护送李去地检办公室
Ryan and Esposito will escort Lee to the D.A.'s office
所经过的路程都是安排好的
via a prearranged route.
每个街角和道路中段都有便衣
We'll have plainclothes in place on every corner and mid-block,
还会有空警支援
and there'll also be air support,
-物尽其用  -机会不多
- for what it's worth. - Not a whole lot.
没人知道拉斯伯恩长什么样
No one even know what Rathborne looks like.
锁定目标应该不会太难
He shouldn't be too hard to spot.
是的  他就是那个想干掉你的人
Yeah, he'll be the one who's trying to kill you.
我们出发吧
All right, let's go, everybody.
请注意  我们向南往拉斐特街
Be advised, we are southbound Lafayette
向渥什街靠近
approaching Worth.
收到  渥什街
Roger on Worth.
确认交叉路口没问题了就告诉我
Let me know when you clear the intersection.
通过交叉路口
We're through the intersection.
渥什街继续向东行
Continuing eastbound Worth.
计划很周详的
It's a solid plan.
我们进入了停车场
We're entering the parking garage.
要注意了
Eyes out.
这个家伙似乎喜欢近距离下手
This guy's supposed to like close-up work.
请注意  我们已经下车了
Be advised. We are now on foot.
拉斯伯恩行动了
Rathborne's making his move.
趴下
On the ground!
扔下枪  不准动
Drop it! Drop it! Don't move!
你们发什么神经
What the hell's wrong with you?
只是手机
It's a phone.
解除警报  不是他
Disregard. Disregard. It's not him.
我们打草惊蛇了  拉斯伯恩没有出现
We must have spooked him. Rathborne didn't show.
我还是让母亲失望了
I let her down.
不  你没有
No, you didn't.
拉斯伯恩影儿都没见
Rathborne's in the wind.
迪克·库南马上要被释放
Dick Coonan's about to walk.
有些地方肯定疏忽了
I missed something.
也许是我疏忽了
Could've been me.
拉斯伯恩可能追查了账号
Rathborne could've checked the routing number,
发现钱是我汇的  而不是迪克
realized the money was coming from my account, not Dick's.
我真是太自大了
I was arrogant.
我可不这么想  卡塞尔
I didn't think you were arrogant, Castle.
我觉得你做得实在是太体贴了
I thought what you did was sweet.
-我会把钱还你的  -不用了  幽灵骑士
- And I will pay you back as - Negative, ghostrider.
这只是为了抓住
Small price to pay
谋害你母亲凶手的小小代价
for a shot at your mother's killer.
杀害她的凶手
Her killer?
什么
What?
库南说需要10万抓住杀害她的凶手
Coonan said it was 100 grand to catch her killer.
但是你从没跟他说被杀的是你母亲
And you never told him it was your mother that was murdered.
从来就没有拉斯伯恩  你编了一个来脱身
There was no Rathborne. That was just a cover.
杀手就是你
It was you.
真是聪明啊
Clever girl.
好啦
All right.
现在听我的
Now here's what's gonna happen.
我们一起慢慢走到电梯那里
We're just gonna stroll on over to the elevator together,
很简单的
nice and easy.
你不会得逞的
That'll never happen.
你出声或是打个暗号
You make a sound, you attempt a signal,
只要是清清喉咙
you so much as clear your throat,
我就对着他的肝来一下
and I'll put a round in this man's liver.
他会在剧痛中慢慢死去
And he will die slowly and in considerable pain.
我们走吧
Let's go.
现在观众没有言简意赅的话要说吗
What, no pithy remarks from the peanut gallery?
作家亲自面对死亡没什么好玩的吧
Not so funny facing your own death, is it?
我不知道  迪克  不如你告诉我吧
I don't know, Dick. You tell me.
据我所知  这里可是警察局
Last time I checked, this was a police station.
我抓你之前  你就知道了  对吗
You knew before I arrested you, didn't you?
你知道我母亲是被你杀的
You knew my mom was your victim.
不涉及个人问题  只不过是活儿
It wasn't personal, okay? She was just another job.
她可是我的母亲  谁雇你杀她的
She was my mother. Who hired you to kill her?
算了吧  你永远不可能抓到他们
Forget it. You'll never touch 'em.
-他们会先把你给解决了  -告诉我  是谁
- They'll bury you. - Tell me who.
不要  长官
No. No. No! Sir!
-我需要他活着  -没错  你的确需要
- I need him alive. - That's right. You do need me.
让他闪开  否则卡塞尔死定了
Now back him off, or Castle dies.
长官  请退开
Sir, back off please.
你知道我不能这么做
You know I can't do that.
你想知道谁雇我杀了你老妈
You want to learn who ordered the hit on your mommy?
最好让我离开这里
You better make sure I make it outta here.
罗伊  求你了
Roy... please.
这就对了  很简单的
That's right Roy. Nice and easy.
这很容易
Nice and easy.
别死
Come on!
Come on.
不要死
Stay with me.
三  四  不要死啊
Three. Four. Come on. Stay with me.
不要死  振作点
No. Come on. Stay with me.
一  二  三  四  五  六  七  八
One. Two.Three. Four. Five. Six. Seven. Eight.
蒙哥马利写的事件报告
Oh. Montgomery's post-incident evaluation.
你的表现像极了史蒂文·席格[动作男星]
You come off like Steven Seagal.
你是恭维我  还是拿我开涮
Should I be flattered or insulted?
都有
Both.
我不知道你现在想吃什么
I didn't know what you felt like,
所以我买了寿司
so... I got sushi,
意大利菜  泰国菜
I got some italian, got some thai,
还买了些热狗
and I grabbed some hot dogs
弄成这样不是你的错
It wasn't your fault, you know.
我拖累你了
I overstepped.
我来是为了要说对不起
I came down here to say that I was sorry
然后我就不来了
and that I'm through.
我不能再跟着你转了  如果不是因为我
I can't shadow you anymore. If it wasn't for me--
如果不是你  我永远不会
If it wasn't for you, I would've never
查出杀害我妈妈的凶手
found my mom's killer.
很快就有这么一天
And someday soon,
我会抓到那个指使
I'm gonna find the sons of bitches
库南杀害我妈妈的混蛋
who had Coonan kill her.
当我抓住凶手时  我希望你能看到
And I'd like you around when I do.
如果你告诉任何人  我接下来所说的话
And if you tell anyone what I'm about to say,
我会干掉你
there's gonna be another shooting,
你的耍花枪我很受用
but... I've gotten used to you pulling my pigtails.
我的工作不轻松  卡塞尔
I have a hard job, Castle,
有你在这儿  可以让工作多些乐趣
and having you around makes it a little more fun.
我会帮你保守这个秘密
Your secret's safe with me.